Guide to the David Nelson Beach, Jr. Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
David Nelson Beach, Jr. Papers
1862-1989
RG 60A
Yale University Divinity School Library
9
(24 boxes)
Correspondence, writings, collected material, and biographical records provide valuable documentation of Beach's Yale education, his work with the YMCA in France during World War I, his ministry, his contributions to the Congregational denomination, and the work of the Connecticut Civil Rights Commission. David Nelson Beach, Jr. (1894-1990) was a clergyman in New England and Minnesota, including at First Church of Christ (Center Church) in New Haven from 1943 to 1960. He served on the Connecticut Civil Rights Commission from 1948 to 1960 and played an influential role in the denominational merger that created the United Church of Christ in 1957.
Beach, David Nelson, 1894-1990
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Barbara Beach Alter.
Biographical / Historical
1894 Jun 17 Born in Cambridge, MA, son of Lillian Tappan Beach and David Nelson Beach, who was minister of Prospect Street Church, Cambridge, and later President of Bangor Theological Seminary
1912 Graduated from Phillips Academy
1916 B.A., Yale College, Phi Beta Kappa
1916-17, 1919-20 Study at Bangor Theological Seminary, before and after YMCA service in France; received B.D. from Bangor in 1927
1917 Jul 22 Married Marguerite Mills, who became the mother of their five children
1918 American Expeditionary Force, YMCA service in France
1918-1919 Ordained for chaplaincy; post-war service as YMCA Secretary at Boston University and University of Maine
1919-1920 Student minister, Congregational Church in Millinocket, ME
1920-1924 Minister, First Church, Guilford, CT
1922 Finished seminary work, received B.D., Yale Divinity School
1924-1927 Minister, Park Place Congregational Church, Pawtucket, RI
1927-1932 Minister, Payson Park Church, Belmont, MA
1932-1936 Minister, First Church, Springfield, MA
1933 D.D., American International College
1936-1943 Minister, Plymouth Church, Minneapolis, MN
1943-1960 Minister, First Church of Christ (Center Church), New Haven. While in New Haven he was chaplain of the Revolutionary Second Company Governor's Footguard, first Chairman of the Human Relations Council, President of the Yale Divinity School Alumni Council
1948-1960 Member of the Connecticut Civil Rights Commission (formerly know as Inter-Racial Commission); Chairman of Commission 1954-1955
1959 Chairman of General Council Commission on Interchurch Relations and Christian Unity
1959-1960 Moderator of General Association of Connecticut and the New Haven Association
1960-1964 Minister, West Dennis Community Church, Cape Cod
1964-1976 Part-time pastorate at Short Beach Community Church, Branford, CT
1990 Jun 25 Died
Scope and Contents
I. Family Correspondence, 1913-1927, n.d.
II. General Correspondence, 1913-1989, n.d.
III. Notes and Writings, 1913-1984, n.d.
IV. Records Related to Merger forming UCC, 1947-1981, n.d.
V. Records Related to Civil Rights, 1948-1981, n.d.
VI. Biographical Documentation, 1898-1985, n.d.
These papers continue the story of the Beach Family begun in Record Group 60, which primarily documents the life and work of David Nelson Beach, Jr.'s father, David Nelson Beach, and his uncle, Harlan P. Beach. Descendant of established New England families, graduate of Yale College and Yale Divinity School, David Nelson Beach, Jr. was a respected and influential clergyman for more than half a century, and a systematic "keeper" of records. Besides providing biographical information, Beach's papers include valuable, thorough documentation of two movements in which he was a key player: the movement toward merger of the Congregational Christian Churches and the Evangelical and Reformed Church to form the United Church of Christ, and the Connecticut Civil Rights Commission.
The Family Correspondence of Series I all dates from before 1928 and is primarily between Beach and his fiancé/wife Marguerite Mills Beach or Beach and his parents and siblings. Extensive correspondence from the 1915 to 1918 time period documents Beach's life as a student at Yale and Bangor Theological Seminary, and his service with the YMCA in France during World War I.
The General Correspondence of Series II is not extensive, but provides an overview of Beach's activities in the churches and organizations with which he was involved, including First Church (Center Church) in New Haven. Much of the substantial correspondence of the record group is contained in Series IV and V with the records documenting the Congregational merger and the Connecticut Civil Rights Commission.
The notes in Series III date primarily from Beach's years at Yale College, providing a thorough record of his undergraduate coursework. Beach's writings include sermons and articles related to the nature of Congregationalism. Other notes, drafts, and writings by Beach are contained in Series IV and V.
Series IV contains a variety of records related to the merger that formed the United Church of Christ in 1957, including legal briefs, letters, memos, notes, and material documenting the role of Beach and Center Church, New Haven. These records of a key player who was in favor of the merger provide an important complement to similar records in Record Group No. 52, the Papers of Henry David Gray, an influential opponent of the merger.
Beach's twelve years of service on what was first called the Connecticut Inter-Racial Commission and then the Connecticut Civil Rights Commission came at a crucial period in the development and enforcement of civil rights in the United States. The thorough Commission records retained by Beach include minutes, letters, memos, cases of appeal, conference reports, and other documentation providing a vivid picture of the civil rights climate in Connecticut and surrounding states from 1948 to 1960.
Series VI, Biographical Documentation, includes a variety of materials shedding light on Beach as an individual, his family, and the organizations with which he was involved during his long and active career.
Arrangement
I. Family Correspondence, 1913-1927, n.d.
II. General Correspondence, 1913-1989, n.d.
III. Notes and Writings, 1913-1984, n.d.
IV. Records Related to Merger forming UCC, 1947-1981, n.d.
V. Records Related to Civil Rights, 1948-1981, n.d.
VI. Biographical Documentation, 1898-1985, n.d.
Civil rights -- Connecticut; Congregational churches -- United States; Congregationalism; Clergy; Beach, David Nelson, 1894-1990; First Church in New Haven (New Haven, Conn.); National Association of Congregational Christian Churches (U.S.); United Church of Christ
- Family Correspondence, Series I
  - To DNB, Jr., from his wife
    - To DNB, Jr. from Marguerite Mills (Beach), 1913-1915 Aug (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1915 Sep-Dec (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1916 Jan-Feb (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1916 Mar-Apr (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1916 May-Jun (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1916 Aug-Dec (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1917 Jan-Jun 12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1917 Jun 16- Jul (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1917 Aug- Dec (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1918 Jan- Apr (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1918 May-Dec (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 1919 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 1923 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - 1926 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - From DNB, Jr., to his wife
    - DNB, Jr. to Marguerite Mills (Beach), 1913-1915 Aug (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 1915 Sep- 1916 Feb (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - 1916 Mar- Aug (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 1916 Sep- Dec (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - 1917 Jan- Jul (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - 1917 Aug- Dec (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - 1918 Jan- May (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - 1918 Jun- Aug (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - 1918 Nov- Dec (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - 1919 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - 1920-1927 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - DNB, Jr., from family
    - 1908-1927, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - DNB, Jr., to family
    - 1916 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - 1917 Jan- Apr (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - 1917 May- Aug 7 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - 1917 Aug 11- Dec (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - 1918 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - 1919 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - 1920 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - 1921 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - 1922 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - 1923 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - 1924 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - 1925 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - 1926 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- General Correspondence, 1913-1916; Series II
  - 1913-1916 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - 1917-1918 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - 1919 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - 1920 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - 1921 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - 1922 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - 1923 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - 1924 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - 1925 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - 1926, 1939, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - incl. re. decision to accept pastorate at Center Church, New Haven, letters from Charles R. Brown and Luther A. Weigle, 1943 Mar- Apr (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - incl. re. decision to accept pastorate at Center Church, New Haven, 1943 May- Jun (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - incl. re. move to accept pastorate at Center Church, New Haven, 1943 Jul- Sep (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - 1947-1950 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - 1951-1954 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - 1955-1957 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - 1960-1961 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - 1962-1964 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - 1966-1980 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - 1981-1989 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - n.d. (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Additional correspondence is contained in Series III - V
- Notes and Writings, Series III
  - Class Notes and Essays
    - Introduction to the Greek New Testament, 1916-1917 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - New Testament Introduction, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - History of New Testament Times, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - New Testament Theology (Prof. Frank Chamberlin Porter), 1921-1922 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - NT - Synoptics, 1919? (Box 7, Folder 66,77)
    - NT - Gospel of John, Johannine literature, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - NT - Romans 1-8, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - NT - Roman 9-16, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - NT - Corinthians I II, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - NT - Galatians, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - NT - Philippians, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - NT - Thessalonians I II, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - NT - Christological epistles, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 85)
    - NT - Pastoral epistles, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 86)
    - NT - Catholic epistles, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 87)
    - NT - Hebrew, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 88)
    - NT - Revelation, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 89)
    - Old Testament Theology, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 90)
    - Old Testament Literature (Prof. C. G. Cumming, Bangor), 1919-1920 (Box 7, Folder 91, 92)
    - OT- Ruth, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 93)
    - OT - Jeremiah, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 94)
    - Age of Johnson, 1916 (Box 7, Folder 95)
    - Age of Shakespeare, 1915-1916 (Box 8, Folder 96, 97)
    - Age of Spenser, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 98)
    - Anthropology, 1914-1915 (Box 8, Folder 99)
    - Apologetics (Prof. Garvie), 1916 (Box 8, Folder 100)
    - Biology, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 101)
    - Christology, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 102)
    - Comparative Politics, 1914-1915 (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - Contemporary Dramatists, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - Contemporary Europe, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 105)
    - English, 1913-1914 (Box 8, Folder 106)
    - English Grammar, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 107)
    - English Literature - 17th cen., 1915-1916 (Box 8, Folder 108)
    - Ethics, 1916, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 109)
    - European History, 476-1816, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 110)
    - The French Revolution, 1915-1916 (Box 9, Folder 111)
    - Greek History, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 112)
    - Hebrew Language, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 113)
    - History of Philosophy, 1914-1915 (Box 9, Folder 114)
    - Modern Idealism, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 115)
    - Philosophy of Religion, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - Poetry of Poe, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 117)
    - Psychology, 1916-1917 (Box 9, Folder 118)
    - Psychology of Childhood (Prof. E. Hershey Sneath), 1920 (Box 9, Folder 119)
    - Psychology of Christian Experience, Psychology of Religion, 1916, 1921 (Box 9, Folder 120)
    - Roman History, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 121)
    - Systematic Theology (Prof. D. C. Macintosh), 1921 (Box 9, Folder 122)
    - United States History, 1914-1916 (Box 9, Folder 123, 124)
    - Church History - Ages I - III, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 125- 127)
    - Church History - Ages IV-VI, 1920, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 128, 129)
    - Church History - modern, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 130)
    - History of Christian Doctrine (Box 10, Folder 131)
    - Christianity in England (Box 10, Folder 132)
    - China as a Mission Field (Prof. Harlan P. Beach), 1920 (Box 10, Folder 133)
    - Homiletics (Dean Charles R. Brown), 1915-1916 (Box 10, Folder 134)
    - Homiletics (Prof. Henry Hallam Tweedy), 1920-1921 (Box 10, Folder 135)
    - Ministerial Ethics (Prof. Tweedy), 1922 (Box 10, Folder 136)
    - The Minister's Message (Dean Brown), 1921 (Box 10, Folder 137)
    - Pastoral Theology, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 138)
    - Congregational Polity (Prof. Tweedy), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 138a)
    - Misc. class papers and short writings, 1917-1920 (Box 10, Folder 139)
  - Writings of DNB, Jr.
    - Thesis: "Certain Conditions and Tendencies in Practical Theology as Taught Today", 1921 (Box 10, Folder 140)
    - Sermons and talks;"Farewell Sermons preached in Plymouth Church"; "Let Congregationalism March Forward in 1960"; "The Historic Continuities of Conciliar Congregationalism, 1648-1961"; "A Sure Heritage", 1923-1943 1960-1964 (Box 10, Folder 141)
    - "Freedom for Responsibilitiy in American Congregationalism"; "A Husband's Tribute to his Wife";autobiographical writings; misc. sermon notes, 1974- 1984, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 142)
    - "Words of Might" - three months' cycle of Scripture passages; "In My Own Right" - an introduction to personal devotions, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 142a)
    - See Boxes 15 and 16 for various drafts and notes by DNB related to Congregationalism
    - See Box 19 for writings of DNB related to Civil Rights
- Records Related to Merger forming UCC, 1947-1948; Series IV
  - Proposals for merger of The Congregational Christian Churches and The Evangelical and Reformed Church, 1947-1948 (Box 11, Folder 143)
  - Defendant's trial brief: Cadman Memorial Congregational Society against Helen Kenyon, Moderator of the General Council of the CCC, 1949? (Box 11, Folder 144)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1949 Feb- May (Box 11, Folder 145)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1949 Aug-Dec, n.m. (Box 11, Folder 146)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1950 Jan- May (Box 11, Folder 147)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1950 Jun- Nov, n.m. (Box 11, Folder 148)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 149)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 150)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1953 May- Nov (Box 11, Folder 151)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1953 Dec, n.m. (Box 11, Folder 152)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1954 Jan- Feb (Box 11, Folder 153)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1954 Mar (Box 12, Folder 154)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1954 Apr-May (Box 12, Folder 155)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1954 Jun (Box 12, Folder 156, 157)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1954 Oct- Dec, n.m. (Box 12, Folder 158)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1955 Jan-Mar (Box 12, Folder 159)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1955 May- Sep (Box 12, Folder 160)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1955 Oct- Nov (Box 12, Folder 161)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1955 Dec, n.m. (Box 12, Folder 162)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1956 Jan-Feb (Box 12, Folder 163)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1956 Mar- May (Box 12, Folder 164)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1956 Jun- Dec (Box 13, Folder 165)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1956 n.m. (Box 13, Folder 166)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1956 n.m. (Box 13, Folder 167)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1957 Jan- Jul (Box 13, Folder 168)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1957 Aug- Nov (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1957, n.m. (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1958 Jan- Jul (Box 13, Folder 171)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1958 Aug- Dec, n.m. (Box 13, Folder 172)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1959 Jan- May (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1959 Jun (Box 13, Folder 174)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1959 Jul- Dec (Box 14, Folder 175)
  - Documents, opinion poll, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 176)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, recommendation of New Haven Association, Constitution of UCC, 1960 Jan-Jul (Box 14, Folder 177)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1960 Sep-Dec, n.m. (Box 14, Folder 178)
  - Review Committees reports, DNB report to Board of Deacons of Center Church, New Haven, Center Church Amendment, 1960-1961 (Box 14, Folder 179)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1961 Jan- Feb (Box 14, Folder 180)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1961 Mar- Jun (Box 14, Folder 181)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1961 Jul- Dec, n.m. (Box 14, Folder 182)
  - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 14, Folder 183)
  - "How Church Union Came" by Malcolm K. Burton, article re. Mayflower Congregation Church lawsuit, 1966, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 184)
  - Material re. Congregationalism, incl. memo of John T. Beach re. misuse of term "congregation", notes of DNB, 1974-1981 (Box 15, Folder 185- 194)
  - Material re. Congregationalism, merger; notes and drafts of DNB (Box 16, Folder 195- 203)
- Records Related to Civil Rights, Series V
  - Connecticut Inter-Racial Commission
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 17, Folder 204)
    - Conference of Commissions of CT, MA, NJ, NY, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 205)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 206)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 207)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 208)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1950 Jan- May (Box 17, Folder 209)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1950 Jun- Dec (Box 17, Folder 210)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence; Education Committee, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 211)
    - Eastern States Conference of Commissions Against Discrimination, 1950 Jun (Box 17, Folder 212)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1951 Jan- Apr (Box 17, Folder 213)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1951 May- Jun (Box 17, Folder 214)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1951 Jul- Dec (Box 17, Folder 215)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence; Education Committee, 1951-1952 (Box 18, Folder 216)
  - Civil Rights Commission
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 217)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence; Education Committee, Inter-Group Relations Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 18, Folder 218)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 18, Folder 219)
    - Draft of "Training Negroes in the Skilled Trades in Connecticut", 1954 (Box 18, Folder 220)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 221)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 222)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 224)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 225)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, incl. interview with DNB, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 226)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 19, Folder 227)
    - Report: "Comparative Study of Negro and White Dropouts in Selected Connecticut High Schools" by Henry G. Stetler, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 228)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 229)
  - Writings and collected material
    - DNB writings: "The Federal Civil Rights Commission and Compliance by Conciliation", "The Right of Petition and the Programs of State Public Agencies Involved in the Field of Discrimination", 1957, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 230)
    - DNB draft writings on civil rights, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 231)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1951-1958 (Box 19, Folder 232)
    - Documents, memos, correspondence, 1963-1966 (Box 19, Folder 233)
    - Newspaper clippings and magazine articles, 1962-1978 (Box 19, Folder 234)
    - DNB petition to Pres. Reagan re. right to petition of Iran hostages, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 235)
- Biographical Documentation, Series VI
  - DNB, Jr. biographical material
    - Youth, ca. 1898-1910 (Box 20, Folder 236)
    - Yale, 1916 (Box 20, Folder 237)
    - Preparations for France, 1917 Apr- Jul (Box 20, Folder 238)
    - In France with YMCA, 1917 Aug- Dec (Box 20, Folder 239)
    - In France with YMCA and writings re., 1917-1919 (Box 20, Folder 240)
    - Re. YMCA work in France, 1918-1921 (Box 20, Folder 241)
    - In Maine, re. ordination, 1918 Aug-Dec (Box 20, Folder 242)
    - In Maine, New Haven, 1919 (Box 20, Folder 243)
    - In Guilford, 1920 (Box 20, Folder 244)
    - In Guilford, at Yale Divinity School, 1921 (Box 21, Folder 245)
    - In Guilford, YDS, 1922 (Box 21, Folder 246)
    - In Guilford, 1923 (Box 21, Folder 247)
    - In Guilford, Pawtucket, RI, 1924 (Box 21, Folder 248)
    - In Pawtucket, 1925-1926 (Box 21, Folder 249, 250)
    - Personal record books - car expenses, shorthand dictionary, 1927-1949 (Box 21, Folder 251)
    - In Springfield, MA, incl. controversy with Gov. James Curley, 1932, 1936 (Box 21, Folder 252)
    - In New Haven, 1951 (Box 21, Folder 253)
    - In New Haven, 1953-1954 (Box 21, Folder 254)
    - In New Haven, 1955-1958 (Box 22, Folder 255)
    - In West Dennis, MA, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 256)
    - In West Dennis, MA, 1961-1963 (Box 22, Folder 257)
    - In CT; incl. autobiographical sketch, celebration of 60th anniversary of ordination; genealogical information, 1967-1981 (Box 22, Folder 258)
    - Account ledger sheets, 1911-1927 (Box 22, Folder 259)
    - Account ledger sheets, 1928-1929 (Box 22, Folder 260)
    - Account ledger sheets, 1930-1967 (Box 22, Folder 261)
  - Family memorabilia
    - Marguerite Mills Beach: memorabilia, 1905-1916 (Box 22, Folder 262)
    - MMB: memorabilia, 1916-1923, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 263)
    - Photographs: DNB, jr. and family (Box 22, Folder 264)
    - Photographs: friends, classmates, 1912, 1916, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 265)
    - Re. John T. Beach and other family members (Box 22, Folder 265a)
  - Collected material
    - Miscellaneous programs, worship materials, notes, poems, clippings (Box 23, Folder 266-267)
    - Maps of France, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 268)
    - Program material from churches served by DNB, 1951-1982 (Box 24, Folder 269- 273)
    - Rotary Club, 1955-1979 (Box 24, Folder 274)
    - Re. Bangor Theological Seminary, 1913-1918 (Box 24, Folder 275)
    - Re. Bangor Theological Seminary, 1954-1957 (Box 24, Folder 276)
    - Re. Bangor Theological Seminary, 1960-1961 (Box 24, Folder 277)
    - Re. Bangor Theological Seminary, 1862-1964 (Box 24, Folder 278)
    - Re. Bangor Theological Seminary, 1965-1979 (Box 24, Folder 279)
    - Re. Bangor Theological Seminary, 1982-1985 (Box 24, Folder 280)